imstat.org 2018-12-25

# Institute of Mathematical Statistics | Privacy Policy

#### Last updated: 8 May 2018

The Institute of Mathematical Statistics (IMS) is committed to the value of privacy. As you use our websites, you may be prompted to enter information when you:

  * Create a user name and password
  * Use personalization features
  * Purchase a product or service
  * Sign up for a free product or service
  * Participate in email lists
  * Provide feedback

The data collected online from an IMS user is voluntary, although some services are only accessible by registering user details. Information collected may include your name, email address, street address, credit or debit card number or bank account number, job title, society membership, or other related demographic information. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, the IMS will endeavor to keep your information confidential. We focus on using the information as part of the IMS’s service to you and its mission.

Notice to EU Users: The server for imstat.org is located in the United States. By entering information on this site, you are consenting to the transfer of that information to the United States. Your information will be handled in accordance with the IMS’s Privacy Policy.

#### How Collected Information Is Used

The primary purpose of gathering information is to allow the IMS to link a name and contact information to a user ID or browsing experience. Once you have provided appropriate information, you will be enabled to use a variety of products or personalized services, and to access online help or support on our web site. Contact information is used to send orders and to send information about our association. The IMS has a policy not to sell its customer lists to any outside group.

#### How We Work to Keep Information Secure

The IMS takes precautions to protect your information. All connections to our websites are encrypted by default whenever possible. You should always see a secure lock icon for webpages managed by the IMS. We strive to protect your personal information both online and offline. When a registration/order form on an IMS-associated site asks for sensitive information (such as a credit-card number), we use modern, strong encryption methods to protect it. We will only make available the minimal amount of personal information necessary to leadership, members, meeting attendees, vendors, etc.

#### Opt-out for European Union and Other Users

In accordance with EU and other guidelines, you may decline to provide the information requested by the IMS. Please be advised, however, that the IMS may be unable to provide certain services unless such information is provided for security and identification purposes.

#### Correct/Update

Members can change their address and related information in the Profile tab in the Membership Login Tab. Members and other customers can send corrections to IMS at [ims@imstat.org](mailto:ims@imstat.org).

#### Choice/Opt Out

Our site provides you the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications. You can do this by visiting the Membership Login Tab or by emailing [ims@imstat.org](mailto:ims@imstat.org).

#### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive that sometimes links to personally identifiable information about the user. The IMS uses session cookies with different lifetimes based on needed functionality. If you configure your browser to reject cookies, you may still use some, but not all, portions of our site. For example, accessing our online journals requires that your browser accept cookies. We recommend closing browsers and clearing cookies, caches, and browser history on publicly available machines (such as those in libraries) after use.

#### Disclosure of Aggregated and Other Information

We use IP addresses and other user information to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We may share aggregated (i.e., non-individual) demographic information with our partners and advertisers. We use one or more outside credit card processing companies to bill users for goods and services and we will disclose your personally identifiable information to these companies as needed to process your orders and to respond to your requests.

#### Links

The IMS sites contain links to other sites, and other sites have links to the IMS. Please be aware that the IMS is not responsible for the privacy practices (or other practices, goods, services, or content) of other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the IMS.

#### IMS Groups Listservs

Users who participate in IMS listservs may have their messages or postings edited for size and/or content. Submissions to such listservs explicitly grant such editorial rights to IMS staff who reserve the right to remove inappropriate submissions. By participating in an online forum or discussion, you consent to our use or disclosure of any content you submit.

#### Protection of Children’s Personal Information

The IMS sites are general audience sites and do not knowingly collect any personal information from children.

#### Notification of Changes

If we make material changes to our privacy policy, these changes will be posted to our privacy policy page. You should review this page regularly for updates.
